Brown Family Papers, 1825-1912, 1965 (Bulk 1850-1894)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Survey made by John Tinsley for James Brown and A.W. Luster of "100 acres of land including grist and saw mills lying in Montgomery County, Virginia, on both Dry Run adjoining the lands, etc," January 22, 1862.
  - Bill from T.R. Evan to James Brown for dry goods totaling $4.12, October 17, 1862.
  - Tax receipt to John and Thomas Brown showing 2 white and 5 black tithes ($7), County war tax on land and property totaling $9.27, State tax on property and value totaling $37.17 for a total of $53.44, 1862.
  - Tax receipt for Thomas Brown showing County and State tax on property and land totaling $64.98, 1862.
  - Tax receipt for John Brown showing County and State tax for property and land on 234.108 acres of land totaling $36.39, 1862.
  - Receipt written by Peter Surface to Giles Wright for $6.00 sent to him by James Brown for "the deliver of som hogs," November 26, 1862.
  - Receipt written by James ----- to James Brown for $100.00 for 500 lbs of pork, December 11, 1862.
  - Account list of house and land rent for Joseph Collins who was in account with Jas C. Brown, 1862.
- (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Tax receipt on printed form for Jas C. Brown for 1 white tithes at $1.25 and State tax on property and value for $2.00, totaling $3.25, 1863.
  - Tax receipt on printed form for Jas C. Brown for 1 white and 3 black tithes for $5.00, county war tax and State tax on property and land on 297 acres, totaling $74.25. The total for the receipt is $168.07, 1863.
  - Tax receipt on printed form for Jno and Thos W. Brown showing 2 white and 2 black tithes totaling $5.00, County war tax and State tax on property and land totaling $143.30. The total receipt is for $148.30, 1863.
  - Tax receipt for John Brown showing County war tax and State tax on property and land on 234 and 108 acres of land totaling $62.24, 1863.
  - Tax receipt for Thomas Brown showing County war tax and State tax on property and land on 342 acres totaling $111.15, 1863.
  - List of items bought at the sale of William Thomas's belongings including 1 desk, 1 preserve stand, 1 senter table, 1 soffey (sofa?), 1 big kettle, 1 crosscut saw, 1 premium plow, and 10 hogs totaling $293.00, March 1, 1863.
  - List of belongings that James C. Brown bought at William Thomas's (deceased) sale. Same contents as list above, 1863.
  - Receipt by -- A. Ronald to James C. Brown for $150.00 "to be credited on a bond I hold against him," November 27, 1863.
  - Bill of sale to James C. Brown from Miller S. Noell for the sale of a slave, Hannah, age 15. The sale was for $30.00, December 7, 1863.
- (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Tax in kind receipt for 1863 to James Brown from F.J. Winkley of the Commissary's Office, Montgomery W.S. Springs Virginia for 7 bushels of wheat, January 25, 1864.
  - Receipt to J.C. Brown from Q M Office (Quartermaster), Montgomery Springs, Virginia, for Brown's "tax in kind" for 1863. The receipt lists 750 lbs of hay, 35 bushels of corn, and 10 bushels of oats, January 24, 1864.
  - Tax receipt to James C. Brown for 1 white and 3 black tithes totaling $4.00, County tax on property and land totaling $149.68. The total receipt is for $153.68, 1864.
  - A negotiable note showing that A.W. Luster paid $3140.81 to Farmers Bank at Blacksburg on a $2250.00 note, August 16, 1864.
  - Bill from A.W. Luster to James C. Brown for $2329.11 which was received in full on settlement, May 2, 1864.
  - Business tax receipt to Thomas Brown from the collector for $11.64, April 30, 1864.
  - Specific tax receipt to Thomas Brown from the collector in the amount of $50.00, January 28, 1864.
  - Business tax receipt for retail dealers in leather to Thomas W. and J. Brown from the collector in the amount of $1810.00. Also a Soldier's tax for retail dealers in leather in the amount of $15.95, September 12, 1864.
  - Tax in kind receipt from Q M Office to James Brown for 24 bushels of corn, December 20, 1864.
  - Poem written by Dr. W.C. Wilson for Miss A.E. Barnett, May 24, 1864.
  - Note from S.C. Beard asking Miss A.E. Barnett to borrow East Lynn (a book), October 2, 1864.
  - Letter from J.P. Smith saying goodbye to Miss Annie E. Barnett, October 3, 1864.
  - Empty envelope to Miss Annie E. Barnett from Wolf Trap, April 29, 1864.
- (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Tax in kind receipt to Jas C. Brown for 1250 lbs of corn, hay, and oats for 1864, February 26, 1865.
  - Receipt to James Brown from G.-- H-ndern--- for a log chain and wagon totaling $37.85, December 25, 1865.
  - Letter from Annie Davis at the "Female Institute" to Annie Barnett, June 26, 1865.
  - Letter from Annie Davis at the "Female Institute" to Annie Barnett, July 24, 1865.
  - Letter from M.L. Dyerle to her friend Annie Barnett, July 31, 1865.
  - Letter from Pet G. Barnett, school child in Catawba, to his Aunt, July 15, 1865.
  - Letter from Annie Barnett of Salem to her sister, August 20, 1965.
  - An invitation to Miss Ann Barnett to come to the home of Mr. and Mrs. Anderson on Wednesday, April 5 at 7 o'clock, 1865.
  - A promissory note to Jas C. Brown from William Henderson for $20.00, July 4, 1865.
  - Unsigned letter to Major John Thomas at Johnson's Island, May 16, 1865.
  - Letter from C. Black in Catawba to Annie. He is sending her his photograph (not enclosed), December 29, 1865.
  - Promissory note from James Brown to pay -- Henderson $37.80, December 15, 1865.
  - Tax receipt to John Brown for County and State taxes on Property on land totaling $11.48, 1865.
- (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Letter from Annie Barnett of "Long Ford," Catawba to "Sister Annie," February 23, 1866.
  - Bill from T.W. Brown to Robert Liggett in the amount of $8.00 for leather, November 30, 1866.
  - Bill from A.W. Luster & Co. to James C. Brown in the amount of $12.31, August 14, 1866.
  - Letter from Fannie in Alexandria, Virginia, to "My Dear Friend," December 16, 1866.
  - Tax receipt to Thomas Brown for County levy on land and property totaling $5.98, State tax on property and land totaling $11.97 on 342 acres of land. The total receipt is for $17.95, 1866.
  - Written receipt to Jas C. Brown from Lybrook Evans & Co for $10.00 to credit Nathan Scantlin's account, September 18, 1866.
  - Purchase list and bill for Jas. C. Brown from W.F. Effinger (dealer in stoves, tin, and sheet iron ware, etc.) totaling $7.60 for 1866 and $3.65 for 1867.
  - Letter from Annie in Catawba to her sister, April 29, 1866.
  - Letter from C. Black in Roanoke Red Sulphur Springs to Annie, February 2, 1866.
  - Letter from C. Black in Roanoke Red Sulphur Springs to Annie Barnett, September 29, 1866.
  - Letter from Cephalus Black in Roanoke Red Sulphur Springs to Annie, May 7, 1866.
  - Letter from Cephalus Black in Philadelphia to Annie, November 3, 1866.
  - Miscellaneous notes of John and Thomas Brown showing interest owed and some calculation notes, 1866.
  - Bill from Brown & Mitchell Co to J.C. Brown for leather goods and work, such as tanning sheepskin, 1 side upper, 2 sheepskins, mending, hipstraps, making 2 backbands, etc., 1866.
  - Letter from Cephalus Black in Roanoke Red Sulphur Springs to Annie Barnett, August 1866.
- (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Bill from Jas C. Brown to Benjamin McCullick for 6 bushels of corn, 5 bushels of wheat, and 4 months tuition and board for Jinnia, totaling $37.62, August 23, 1867.
  - Bill from Jas. C. Brown to Benjamin McCullick for 6 bushels of corn and 5 bushels of wheat totaling $14.50, August 23, 1867.
  - Bill from Jas. C. Brown to Benjamin McCullick for 4 months tuition and board for Jinnia at $5 per month totaling $20.00, 1867.
  - Bill from Jas. C. Brown to Wm Effinger for 2 bushels of wheat and crediting $2.60 to his account, leaving a balance of $1.40, October 28, 1867.
  - Court summons for James C. Brown to answer William H. Pu-- in a plea of a debt of $65.45 and damages of $65.00, August 2, 1867.
  - Letter from beau in Wytheville to Miss Annie (signature torn off), May 26, 1867.
  - Letter from Cephalus Black to Miss Annie, sending her grapes, September 20, 1867.
  - Letter from Rosa Ramsey in Norfolk to Mr. Brown applying for a teaching "situation," July 27, 1867.
  - Tax receipt to Thomas Brown showing County and State tax on property and 342 acres of land totaling $34.20, 1867.
  - Tax receipt to John Brown showing County and State tax on Property and 234 and 108 acres of land totaling $19.16, 1867.
- (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Bill from Giles Thomas to James Brown for leather totaling $36.43, March 3, 1868.
  - Bill from Jas C. Brown to Thomas W. Brown for lumber totaling $86.92, August 18, 1868.
  - Letter from G.D. Thomas to James C. Brown concerning a debt, 1868.
  - Court summons for James C. Brown, Giles D. Thomas, Achilles W. Luster, Julia E. Thomas, John M. Thomas, Charles, D. Peck, and William H. Thomas to answer Jacob Crumpecker for a debt of $961.44 and damages of $20.00 November 24, 1868.
  - Letter from C. Black (signature cut off) to Annie, October 25, 1868.
  - Letter from C. Black in Red Springs to Annie Barnett, September 20, 1868.
  - Letter to James C. Brown notifying him that the judgement obtained at the September 1867 term of the Circuit Court of Montgomery County by W.H. Peck had been assigned and transferred to H. Black for his benefit. The letter was signed by H. Black, September 3, 1868.
  - Receipt from T.W. Jones & Sons to James C. Brown recording $3.96 to his account, September 17, 1868.
  - "Memorandum of notes in the hands of Giles J. Henderson Trustee" for two notes or bonds totaling $481.88 which were both due in 1857. The note was signed by A.W. Luster, 1868.
  - Letter from N. Walthall, an attorney in Christiansburg, to Jas. C. Brown regarding a judgement to be brought against him, March 30, 1868.
- (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Bill to James Brown for farm work, 1869.
  - Tax receipt to James C. Brown showing 1 tithe at $.50, County and State tax on property and land for 297 and 100 acres of land totaling $42.42. The total for the receipt was $42.92, 1869.
  - Court summons for James C. Brown to answer John M. Hinchee who is suing for the benefit of Ruth Henderson with a plea of debt for $53.19 and damages of $55.00, September 23, 1869.
  - Court summons for James C. Brown to answer Ann H. Hoge who is suing for the benefit of George Earhart, September 27, 1869.
  - Tax receipt for Thomas Brown for 1 tithe at $.50, County and State tax on property and land on 342 acres of land totaling $50.39, 1869.
  - Tax receipt for John Brown for 1 tithe at $.50, County and State tax on property and land on 234 and 108 acres of land totaling $28.70. The total receipt was $29.20, 1869.
  - Bill from James Brown to E.D. Mitchell for oats, rye, a set of four horse harnesses, etc., 1869.
  - Bill and letter to James Brown about 1 barrel N.C. clip herring from M.C. Darby, August 1869.
  - Receipt for 8 1/2 months work that John Caves had done for James Brown, October 13, 1869.
- (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Letter from Palmer, Hartsock & Co. to Mrs. Ann E. Brown about a "firkin of butter," December 28, 1870.
  - Tax receipt to James Brown showing 1 tithe at $.50, County and State tax on property and land for 297 and 100 acres of land totaling $57.84. The total for the receipt was $58.34, 1870.
  - Court summons for James C. Brown to appear in court to answer to Francis Henderson for a debt of $463.67 and damages of $463.00, June 27, 1870.
  - Letter from F.H. Grupy & Co. to Mr. Thomas Brown explaining the supply of oil they just received and asking if Brown wants an order, March 30, 1870.
  - Bill from D.A. Brown to J.C. Brown for miscellaneous clothing items showing the remaining balance of $28.13, October 27, 1870.
  - Three commission sales and bills that were pinned together to Thomas W. Brown from Jones & Miller, 1870.
  - Letter from Sml G. Johnston to John Brown (2 copies), January 27, 1870.
  - Short letter from J.M Wade to James Brown asking to "probate T.W. Brown's will," June 1870.
  - Note from J.M.Wade to James Brown: "To Clerk Montgomery Circuit Court ado Lybrook S.P. attorney 10 plea 15 order 36," October 1870.
  - Promissory note from Jas C. Brown to H. Black promising to pay $142.34, July 15, 1870.
  - Note from J.C. Brown to T.W Tucker in settlement of $29.60 which was later settled on 26 August 1871, February 27, 1870.
  - Receipt to James Brown for $1.00 State tax on bond for being one of the executors of Thomas W. Brown's estate, July 4, 1870.
  - Tax receipt to John Brown for 1 tithe, County and State tax on property and land all totaling $39.37, 1870.
  - Note showing that J.C. Brown recorded 2 bushels of wheat for Mal Croy. The note was written by P.R. & W.W. Puckett, December 6, 1870.
  - Letter to T.W. Brown from Jones & Miller in Lynchburg saying that it is "very hard to sell bacon," April 5, 1870.
  - Account sale of butter by Palmer, Hartsock & Co. for Hno. Brown of Blacksburg, December 10, 1870.
- (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Bill from D.A. Brown to James Brown totaling $77.14, October 3, 1871.
  - Receipt to J.B. Helm by ----- P. Mayo for "Weekly Dispatch" printed by "Richmond Dispatch" for the dates of 24 May 1870 to January 22, 1871.
  - Bill from H. Wallerstein & Co. to J.C. Brown for wheat and oats. Note: evidently they had sold this on behalf of Brown, a total of $190.50, for next are listed "charges" for R.R. freight and hire on 90 bags and commission on sales, September 5, 1871.
  - Bill from P.P. & W.W. Puckett to Jas. C. Brown for flour, wheat, and buck wheat flour, some for himself and some orders for other people. The total was $147.50, December 8, 1871.
  - Bill from Jacob H. Moses to James Brown for repairing a buggy, "dr 2 old shoes", and a welding heal on a mowing blade, 1871.
  - Tax receipt for Thomas Brown on 342 acres of land totaling $16.44, 1871.
  - Tax receipt for Jas C. Brown on 397 acres of land totaling $14.15, 1871.
  - Tax receipt for James Brown totaling $74.48, 1871.
  - Note explaining the judgement is granted in favor of the plaintiff for $753.00 with interest, March 18, 1871.
  - Tax receipt for Thomas Brown on 342 acres of land totaling $4.04, 1871.
  - Letter to Annie from A.E. Barnett containing a recipe for blackberry wine (2 copies), july 13, 1871.
- (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Promissory note from author unknown stating that they promise to pay Burd Anderson $376.00, October 18, 1872.
  - Letter to J.C. Brown from the Clerk of Disrtict Court saying that Lybrook had declared bankruptcy, March 7, 1872.
  - Promissory note to Isaac Henderson from Jas C. Brown promising to pay $20.00, March 30, 1872.
  - General merchandise bill from T.A. Roberts to Jas C. Brown totaling $101.73, 1872.
  - Letter addressed to T.W. and J.C. Brown from an agent, A.W. Hamilton, for C.H. McCormick & Bros. asking to pay a debt of $130.00 with interest of $10.00 that they owe, January 4, 1872.
  - Short letter to James Brown from John Richard asking if Jacob Oliver can have "two horse load of hay," March 1872.
  - Subpoena notice for J.C. Brown from the sheriff, 1872.
  - Letter and bill from Valley Mills Foundry to James C. Brown asking for the money that Brown owes, August 12, 1872.
  - Letter to T.W. and J.C. Brown about money that they owe H. McCormick & Bros, signed by their General Agent, A.M. Hamilton, February 12, 1872.
  - Letter to Jas Brown from Wm. J. Hopkins about the balance due on a machine, February 11, 1872.
  - Letter to James Brown from T.A. Roberts asking if Brown will give a friend some pork and Roberts will credit his bill, December 2, 1872
  - Cobbler's bill totaling $12.90, 1872.
- (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Memorandum on an "Article of Agreement" between James C. Brown and Gilder Henderson regarding the sale of land, livestock, etc., 1873.
  - Note stating that Jas.C. Brown promises to pay H. Black $198.48 but Brown's handwriting is crossed out, March 5, 1873.
  - Note stating that Jas C. Brown promises to pay D.W. Frizzell $162.60 but Brown's signature has been crossed out, June 24, 1873.
  - Merchandise bill of James Brown from Thos. W. Jones & Son for a total of $17.15, February 25, 1873.
  - Letter to Jas C. Brown from E.V. Mitchell concerning a bill, January 15, 1873.
  - Summons for J.C. Brown and Thomas M. Brown appear in court to face Cyrus H. McCormick and Leander J. McCormick in a plea of a debt of $130.00 and damages of $130.00, July 19, 1873.
  - Receipt from Henry Brown to Thomas W. Brown stating that all accounts between them are in full, September 19, 1873.
  - Letter from Valley Mills Foundry to James C. Brown stating that they will ship his plow points, December 8, 1873.
  - Tuition bill for "Miss Mollie" for two months of grade school to J.C. Brown from J.H. Turner, December 4, 1873.
  - Letter to James Brown from Joel Thomason about the sale of a Huffman drill, July 19, 1873.
- (Box-folder 1:30)
  - Receipt from the Sheriff of Montgomery County to J.C. Brown in the amount of $45.24, 1874.
  - Bill to James Brown for one mare in fold for $14.00, May 20, 1874.
  - Letter to James Brown from P.B. Sale concerning a bill for fruit trees, March 23, 1874.
  - Letter from H.A. Edmundson to James Brown concerning Brown's suit against James Barenett, March 27, 1874.
  - Letter and bill to James Brown from E.O. Galloway concerning a cobbler's bill, September 1, 1874.
  - Letter from Valley Mills Foundry to James Brown concerning the amount of Brown's account, March 11, 1874.
  - Letter from Wm. Woods to Jas Brown, April 10, 1874.
  - General merchandise bill from D.W. Frizzell to James Brown totaling $15.32, 1874.
  - Blacksburg Township bill to James Brown for taxed on 297 acres of land and property and income totaling $5.93, 1874.
  - List of names and amounts totaling $1128.14, January 10, 1874.
  - Printed and handwritten letter to Mrs. A.E. Brown from Thomas F. West, attorney at law, concerning a collection of $36.00 owed for nine years of subscription to "The Central Presbyterian," April 21, 1874.
  - Summons note for James Brown to appear in court and face David W. Frizzell who is suing for the benefit of Johnson Sutton & Co., December 18, 1874.
  - Blacksmith bill of James Brown totaling $14.93, 1874.
  - Letter, bill, and railroad bill for plow casting from F.G. & W.J. Keller to J.C. Brown, 1874.
  - Letter from E.W. Peck to Mrs. Brown concerning a stove, etc, August 26, 1874.
- (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Tax bill for Thomas Brown (J.C. Brown to pay) on 342 acres of land totaling $47.25, May 10, 1875.
  - Agreement made by J. Wells, G. Wells, and J.C. Brown concerning the building of a house, 1875.
  - Farm work bill for 1875-1877, Jas.C. Brown in account with John Scanland, 1875.
  - Blacksmith bill of J.C. Brown totaling $46.06, 1875.
  - General merchandise bill to J.C. Brown from T.W. Helm concerning the amount that Brown owes, May 8, 1875.
  - Letter from Wilmere Barnett to Aunt Ann (Mrs. John Brown) stating that she will marry Mr. Jopling, April 29, 1975.
  - Blacksmith bill of J.C. Brown, 1875.
  - General merchandise bill to James Brown of items that he bought of Persinger & Peck, 1875.
  - Promissory note to Daniel S. Slusher from J.C. Brown promising to pay $45.00, July 23, 1875.
  - Doctor bill from H. Black to James Brown. The doctor was --- Jackson M.D., 1875.
- (Box-folder 1:32)
  - Whiskey bill to James Brown totaling $4.00, 1876.
  - Bill for 1/2 stack of hay for Mr. Ellen from Ja. C. Brown, April 24, 1876.
  - Note to Mr. Brown from W.H. Gad---- concerning 55 lbs of flour, July 3, 1876.
  - Letter to J.C. Brown from Eldred R. Anderson regarding a note transferred to Anderson by Floyd Smith, July 13, 1876.
  - Letter from H. Wallerstein & Co. to J,C, Brown concerning a check that the company is sending to Brown in the amount of $75.77, September 11, 1876.
  - Letter from Bell & Co. to James Brown in which the company proposes a settlement of a bill by barter, August 23, 1876.
  - Bill to D.C. Mooman from Jas.C. Brown for nine logs in the amount of $9.00, 1876.
  - Bill to C.A. Deyerle from John Brown concerning suit clothes, July 1, 1876.
  - Letter from Lula Barnett in Musk Grove to her cousin Mary George Barnett, December 22, 1876.
  - Blacksmith bill from Ezekial Dowdy to J.C. Brown totaling $14.64, 1876.
  - County tax bill for James Brown on 297 acres of land and property, income, etc. The total tax was $ 78.58, 1876.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown to Giles D. ---mas in the amount of $36.95, June 16, 1876.
  - Promissory note from Jas.C. Brown to H. Black in the amount of $102.46, May 24, 1876.
- (Box-folder 1:33)
  - Blacksmith bill from E. Dowdy to J.C. Brown in the amount of $3.40, 1877.
  - General merchandise bill from J.N. Johnston to Jas. C. Brown totaling $25.65, 1877.
  - Receipt for payment in full of judgement of J.C. Brown to C.A. Ronald for G.W. Snider, January 4, 1877.
  - Bill from Jas. C Brown to Elleck Nutter for corn and beef totaling $77.90, 1877.
  - County tax bill for James C. Brown on 297 acres of land and property, income, etc. totaling $75.51, 1877.
  - Blacksmith bill to J.C. Brown, 1877.
  - Account sales of wheat to Hoxall Mills from Silas Shelburn in the amount of $41.06, August 30, 1877.
  - Note saying that John Brown recorded the amount in full of James Brown's account, July 21, 1877.
  - Due bill to Ezekiel Dowdy by J.C Brown for the amount of $19.50, April 30, 1877.
  - Amounts in the law suit of D.H. Hoge vs. Jno W. Brown and James C. Brown, 1877.
  - Blacksmith bill to J.C. Brown totaling $8.91, 1877.
  - Due bill from Jas. C Brown to T.W. Tucker in the amount of $8.00, August 26, 1877.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown to W.H. Thomas in the amount of $37.00, September 18, 1877.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown to Giles D. Thomas in the amount of $32.64, November 20, 1877.
- (Box-folder 1:34)
  - Promissory note from Jas C. Brown to -H Black in the amount of $119.75, August 5, 1878.
  - General merchandise bill from Bell & Sons to Jas.C. Brown, 1878
  - "Article of Agreement" between William Ratliff and Jas.C. Brown concerning a farm work contract, October 11, 1878.
  - Bill to J.C. Brown from Ephrigm Sights for corn and hay in the amount of $10.67, 1878.
- (Box-folder 1:35)
  - Names in an old ledger found in the attic of James Brown's farmhouse, 1878-1890.
- (Box-folder 1:36)
  - Three page ledger bill from James C. Brown to Howe Brown for general merchandise, 1879.
  - County tax bill for James C. Brown on 297 acres at $5,940.00 plus property, income, etc. valued at $403.00. The total bill was $69.89, 1879.
  - Deed signed by Jas.C. Brown granting land to his wife, Ann E. Brown, August 5, 1879.
- (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Cobbler's bill to J.C. Brown in account with A.V. Lawerance totaling $9.10, 1880.
  - Deed made between James C. Brown, his wife, Ann E. Brown, and George G. Junkin concerning a tract of land, June 4, 1880.
  - Letter from American Bible Society, in New York, to D.H. Brown, December 10, 1880.
  - Promissory note from James Brown to John Fink(??) in the amount of $.50, February 5, 1880.
  - Bill from Gardner & Co. to James C. Brown on a settlement of $8.23, October 4, 1880.
  - Merchandise bill for Richard Kingsley for pigs, 1880.
  - Bill for shoes, cloth, and sugar to John Brown totaling $2.35, August 27, 1880.
- (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Handwritten note from Jas C. Brown concerning $4.60 borrowed from E.E. John, and waiving all Homestead Exemptions, July 1881.
  - Bill from N. Conrad to Jas C. Brown for items such as 8 yds of cashmere, 5 yds of black calico, and 1 1/2 yds black wiggin, etc totaling $7.29, December 13, 1881.
  - Letter from G.W. & L.C. Hansbrough, Attorneys and Counsellors at Law, to Jas C. Brown, December 10, 1881.
  - General merchandise bill from N. Conrad to James C. Brown totaling $3.59, 1881.
  - Unfinished letter, author unknown, to "Dear Cousin," October 5, 1881.